





Mob: 07907 617 855

Email: <u>paul.hoang.uk@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>fluffymango.co.uk</u>

N.I: upon request

Github: github.com/General-Meow

Looking for: Contract work Rate: Dependent on role Availability: July

Location: London (no travel)

Nationality: British

# Paul Hoang

#### **Profile**

A self motivated and proactive man, who has over 13 years experience in the IT industry, 11 of which are in Java development. Currently looking for **CONTRACT** roles in **LONDON** around the Java/DevOps space. This role could even be a hybrid role where I could leverage my development experience in Java. Willing to learn on the job and push for excellent results while pushing and mentoring other team members.

#### **Key Technical Skills**

Main Focus - Java 6/7/8 (6 certified) - Spring - Spring Integration - Spring Boot - Spring Batch - GraphQL - Java Spark (Web framework not big data) -

J2EE - Servlets - SQL - Hybris

Front End HTML - JSP - CSS - LessCSS - JavaScript - Typescript - Angular2js

– Jade (PUG) - jQuery – jQuery Mobile – Spring MVC

Servers /
Containers

Tomcat - Jetty - Apache Web server - Nginx

Databases Oracle - MySQL - Hibernate - Schema Design

Methodologies Agile - Object Oriented Programming - Test Driven Design - Domain

Driven Design – Microservices – Cloud - Scrum

DevOps AWS Certified (ECS, API Gateway, EC2, S3, VPC, Route 53,

Security groups etc) - Terraform - Ansible - Docker - docker-compose - Continuous Integration / Deployment (CI/CD) - Jenkins

(Pipelines) – github – Kubernetes (novice)

Other Requirements Capturing – Windows 7/8/10 - Linux – Mac OS -

Netbeans – Intellij Idea - Eclipse - Apache Ant – Maven – Gradle - Mercurial – Git - Subversion - JUnit - Mockito- Technical Design

Documentation – UML – Mentoring - E-Commerce

#### **Employment**

# **August 2019 – June 2020** NHS (HEE)

Senior Fullstack Developer

Joined HEE on the ESR Bi directional integration project. Was a greenfield project to replace the existing system that was developed in haste and was falling apart.

Was part of a small squad using LESS (Scrum) of 3 developers and a BA. Project objectives was to integrate the HEE system (TIS) that holds information on trainees with the system from ESR that deals with PAYE.

We built a microservices based system using Java 11, Spring boot 2, Docker, RabbitMQ, MongoDB all on Azure using VM's created with Terraform and managed with Ansible. It was built using Jenkins pipelines, Azure docker repositories and health checks.

Played an important part of the team to architect the entire integration, selecting technology choices, team sharings and mentoring to ensure handover was smooth.

Partway through the project, I played a leading role in a migration project from Azure to AWS. I pulled the team together in high level sessions to get a common understanding of where we are now and where we wanted to be. This then fed into a more detailed design which then helped in the creation Terraform modules I did. These modules were for the creation of VPC's & subnets, API Gateway, ECS and network load balancers.

At the end of the project, we delivered most of what we initially set out to do, like all Agile projects, you learn new things along the way and they have an effect on scope.

# May 2019 – August 2019 Transform (MMO) Senior Java Developer

Joined Transform on the Marine Management Organisation project. This was a project centred around the logging of caught fish at sea on mobile devices. I was one of two backend developers in charge of developing microservices to integrate with and serve existing services built as part of another project.

This was all build on the Java 11 Spring boot 2 stack, deployed in docker containers using circle ci and Azure. Frontend was MS PowerApps based with Power BI.

#### April 2019 – Present Fluffy Mango DevOps Engineer

After working with the HEE (NHS) for 2 years and gaining some experience of DevOps, I decided to take some time out to widen my skillset in this domain. So I spent time learning Terraform with AWS. I've gotten to a point where I'm comfortable using it as I've gotten to a stage where I'm creating VPC's, Security groups, EC2 Instances all from code.

I've also gotten fluffy mango's website up and running on AWS using static websites feature on S3 and DNS on Route 53.

The plan is to use AWS as a platform to continue my experience with kubernetes and have a fully cloud native app running there with a full CI/CD pipeline

#### Feb 2017 – March 2019 NHS (HEE) Senior Fullstack Developer

Employed as a senior fullstack developer doing mostly backend development in Java 8. Using technologies such as Spring boot (Web, Batch), Hibernate, Flyway, SQL, Docker, Ansible. On the frontend the stack included angular 2 (ng2), angular 1, LessCss.

The team I joined is a medium sized agile team, that had quite a custom workflow. Whereby tasks/stories were not estimated and process was more like ScrumBan.

My later responsibilities moved more into a managing role as a large part of the team moved on. I have recently been trying to fix team dynamics and process by introducing more structure and moving the team towards Scrum. Training and mentoring junior developers has taken more time as well as architecting the solution and fixing technical debt. Other things include working more closer with DevOps as well as working on DevOps related stories, scheduling/running interviews for new team members and running scrum ceremonies.

The project I worked on was the trainee management system that was being deployed nationwide. It was heavily microservices based and ran along side the existing legacy system that was being replaced. This meant that we had master/slave/migration challenges which involved many custom ETL's that ran nightly. Other parts of the system were spun up at a rapid pace using Jhipster which allowed us to create many services within weeks.

# September 2016 – Jan 2017 CrownPeak (Active Senior Fullstack Developer Standards)

Employed as a senior fullstack developer doing mostly frontend development on the in house CMS application. The technology stack included angular 2 (ng2), angular 1, LessCss, Node npm, Bower, Jade (Pug), Visual Studio, Windows 10.

The team I joined is a highly self organised agile team, running grooming sessions, retrospectives, iteration kick off meetings and end of train demos.

#### November 2015 – Sept 2016 e2y

#### **Senior Hybris Developer**

Onsite as a hybris developer contractor. e2y is a young agile company, developing ground breaking e-commerce solutions focusing on high quality code and processes.

While there I designed and developed software solutions for a high end fashion marketplace retailer on the hybris platform. They were using hybris 5.7 with an on going process to upgrade to hybris 6

### August 2015 – Oct 2015 rightmove.co.uk

Senior Fullstack Developer

Rightmove is the number one property listing website, with millions of new properties listed. It provides a platform to allow estate agents to list properties which in turn connects vendors to buyers.

As a senior developer, I worked on a number of the backend tools used by both the business and the estate agents. My time is split between supporting the old applications as well as developing new features for the current system.

#### May 2010 – August 2015 Neoworks (Salmon) Senior Hybris Developer

neoworks is an ecommerce consultancy company, that works with a number of large blue chip companies on their complex ecommerce websites based on the Hybris platform. Recently acquired by Salmon, they have become the best company to approach when using hybris.

As a senior developer, I worked on any aspect that required my skills. From frontend work to backend to integration.

I've worked on a number of projects while at neoworks and some of these are for companies such as: Ted Baker, BBC, Asics, Toys R Us (both desktop and mobile sites), Nikon, The Toyshop, DHL, Target, iStone, HQHair, Urooms and the neoworks website.

Some of the more recent projects used, Java, Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Integration, Spring Roo, Hibernate, Hybris, servlets, mercurial, html, JSP, CSS

July 2007 – May 2010 Bluecycle.com – An Aviva Java Developer (Norwich Union)
Company

My role at Bluecycle required me to continually develop and maintain the current web

application (currently deployed onto JBoss AS 4.2.3). It is currently split approximately 50/50 between application maintenance and development. Maintenance requires skills in technologies such as Struts, JSP, SQL (Oracle), EJB 2 as well as front end development in HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

My last project involved rewriting the frontend of the website to allow push bidding (reverse ajax) on auction items. The technologies involved were Apache wicket and Dojo. We have just started a new work process that is like Agile. It involves user stories, epics, sprints, miles and information radiators.

Over the past year, we have been working on a (Greenfield) project that involves redeveloping a large section of the web application using more modern technologies. These technologies include Domain Driven Design, JBoss Seam, JSF, EJB 3 and Woodstock.

#### **Education**

### **University of Westminster**

2002-2005

BSc Software Engineering Degree 2:2 (for full listing of modules available upon request)

#### Lewisham College

2000-2002

AVCE in ICT (B,B) – (2 year college course, equal to 2 full A Levels)

#### **Deptford Green Secondary School**

1995-2000

GCSE: Maths (B), Science (C,C), English (C,D), Drama (B), I.T (B), Religious Education (C), French (C)

#### Certifications

- Sun Certified Java Programmer 6 (SCJP 6)
- Hybris Core Developer
- Hybris Commerce
- AWS Certified Developer Associate 2017
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate 2017
- Professional Scrum Master (PSM)

#### References

Available upon request

# Additional Information

In my spare time, I enjoy learning about new technologies. These include both PC hardware and web development software. I enjoy building custom PC's that have small footprints (Mini itx) and low power consumption/noise. I have a number of raspberry pi's, all running on different things with the aim to one day play with big data on them and see the limitations on this small platform (ask me for an update if your interested).

Other things I like doing are watching movies, playing computer games and badminton.

Information on additional work experience, voluntary work and academic grades are available on request.